Guide to the William Rose Benét Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Family Correspondence, 1883-1956; Series II; 9.17; 22 boxes
  - Other Family Letters
    - De la Mare, Walter to Laura Benét, 1939 November 28 (Box 71, Folder 2451)
    - Fechel, Mary E. to Frances Rose Benét, [?] October 5 (Box 71, Folder 2452)
    - Fish, Williston to [Frances Rose?] Benét, 1930 December 20 (Box 71, Folder 2453)
    - Halloran, Elizabeth to Frances Rose Benét, 1931 September 6 (Box 71, Folder 2454)
    - Loveman, Amy to Frances Rosemary (Benét) Dawson, 1950 May 18 (Box 71, Folder 2455)
    - Marsh, Marian to Frances Rose Benét, 1930 August 13 (Box 71, Folder 2456)
    - Mayfair Publishing Co. (New York, N.Y.) to [Lora Baxter?], 1928 April 19 (Box 71, Folder 2457)
    - Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States to James Walker Benét, 1904 April 7 (Box 71, Folder 2458)
    - Miller, Mary to Frances Rose Benét, undated (Box 71, Folder 2459)
    - Moore, Marianne to Laura Benét, 1939–1956 (Box 71, Folder 2460)
    - Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation to Laura Benét, 1935 June 12 (Box 71, Folder 2461)
    - Ryder, Elisabeth A. to Frances Rose Benét, 1929 August 9 (Box 71, Folder 2462)
    - St. Augustine Historical Society to Frances Rose Benét, 1937 April 15 (Box 71, Folder 2463)
    - Saturday Review of Literature to Frances Rose Benét, 1932; 1938 (Box 71, Folder 2464)
    - Sisters of Saint Joseph to Frances Rose Benét, 1919 January 31 (Box 71, Folder 2465)
    - Thomas, Norman to Frances Rose Benét, undated (Box 71, Folder 2466)
    - United States. War Dept. Ordnance Office to S. V. (Stephen Vincent) Benét, 1874 Janaury 27 (Box 71, Folder 2467)
    - Wheeler, Thomas T. to Frances Rose Benét, 1907 May 16 (Box 71, Folder 2468)
    - First name only to various, 1919-1950, undated (Box 71, Folder 2469-2470)
    - Unidentified to various, 1906-1947, undated (Box 71, Folder 2471)
- Writings, 1895-1957; Series III; 16.34; 18 boxes + 3 broadside folders
  Organized into two subseries: Writings and Editorial Projects of William Rose Benét and Writings of Others. Writings of William Rose Benét are arranged aphabetically by title or heading. Writings of Others is arranged alphabetically by author.
  Series III. Writings includes manuscript writings by Benét, material relating to editorial projects to which Benét contributed, and writings by others. Printed versions of individual works by Benét with autograph manuscript corrections can be found here, otherwise printed versions of writings by Benét are filed in Series IV.
  The manuscripts of William Rose Benét consist chiefly of drafts of poems and other shorter works. Research material, notes, scenarios, proofs, and production-related material, such as publicity and correspondence, can also be found. Corrected and multiple drafts are common for many titles, showing the evolution of particular texts.
  William Rose Benét is probably best known for his editorial work and poetry. In addition to his long-standing (1923-1950) position with the Saturday Review, Benét contributed to several compilations of English-language poetry and literature. The Writings series includes drafts and other material for unspecified "Anthologies" and for Fifty Poets: An American Auto-Anthology (1933). Drafts and other material relating to individual poems by Benét can be found by title in the alphabetical run of writings or in a group preserved under the supplied heading, [Poems]. Material can also be found for three poetry collections dating from the 1940s, Day of Deliverance:A Book of Poems in Wartime (1944), The Dust Which Is God (1941), a book of autobiographical verse for which Benét was awarded the Pulitzer Prize in poetry in 1942, and The Stairway of Surprise (1948).
  In addition to poetry, Benét authored book reviews, essays, introductions, lectures and addresses, plays, and short stories. There is also material for two unpublished novels, "The Gilded Man" and "The Living Miranda."
  There are also a good number of works by family members, both drafts and printed versions, and by others, some of which were no doubt sent to hared with Benét in his capacity as an editor.
  - Writings and Editorial Projects of William Rose Benét
    - "Address by William Rose Benét"
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1934 October 13 (Box 72, Folder 2472)
    - Adolphus, or, The Adopted Dolphin and The Pirate's Daughter
      - Draft, plan, autograph manuscript, corrected and initialed, undated (Box 72, Folder 2473)
      - Mock up, children's book, undated (Box 72, Folder 2474)
      - Proof, with printer's annotations, 1941 (Box 72, Folder 2475)
    - "Along Their Iron Trestles"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 2476)
    - "Always I Know You Anew"
      - Draft, poem, typescript mimeograph, undated (Box 72, Folder 2477)
    - "American Poetry"
      - Draft, address, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 2478)
    - "American Women Poets"
      - Notes, address, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 2479)
      - Draft of "abstract," address, typescript, corrected, 1935–1937 (Box 72, Folder 2480)
    - "Anatomy of Terror"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 2481)
    - "Anthologies"
      - Drafts and other material, 1929-1936, undated (Box 72, Folder 2482-2484)
      - Clippings removed from drafts and other material, 1929–1930 (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3337)
      - Drafts and other material, 1935, undated (Box 73, Folder 2485-2488)
      - Clipping removed from drafts and other material, 1935 August 11 (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3338)
    - "Apportionment"
      - Printed version, poem, annotated, undated (Box 74, Folder 2489)
    - "The Arsenal"
      - Drafts of "Paper," autograph manuscript, corrected, 1901 (Box 74, Folder 2490)
    - "Arthur at Lonazep"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 74, Folder 2491)
    - "Aviation Engine Production"
      - Draft, essay, typescript carbon, undated (Box 74, Folder 2492)
    - "The Ballad in English Verse"
      - Draft, [lecture?], typescript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2493)
    - "The Ballad: Modern Ballads"
      - Draft, lecture, typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2494)
    - "A Ballad of Gloucester"
      - Fair copy, poem, autograph manuscript, 1943 July (Box 74, Folder 2495)
    - "Ballad of Monsters"
      - Galley proof, corrected, [?] October 19 (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3339)
    - "Ballad of the S. R. L. "
      - Printed version, undated (Box 74, Folder 2496)
    - "Ballad of St. Lewis"
      - Draft, typescript mimeograph, corrected and signed, undated (Box 74, Folder 2497)
    - "Batteries"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2498)
    - "The Bird of Dawning"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2499)
    - "The Black Arrow"
      - Draft, dramatic adaptation, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2500)
    - "Blue Velvet"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2501)
    - "Bread"
      - Copy, poem, typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 May 11 (Box 74, Folder 2502)
    - "The Brigands"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2503)
    - "Buckeyes"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2504)
    - "The Bugle"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2505)
    - "Café Tortoni '81"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, corrected, inscribed, and signed, 1914 April (Box 74, Folder 2506)
    - "The Caravels"
      - Drafts, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3340)
      - Draft, poem, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2507)
    - "The Case of Jaques Ribaut"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2508)
    - "Cat at Versailles"
      - Draft, story, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2509)
      - Draft, story, typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 2510)
      - Draft, story, typescript carbon (2 copies), undated (Box 74, Folder 2511)
    - "The 'Caution' and the 'Aberration'"
      - Draft, story, typescript, corrected and signed, undated (Box 74, Folder 2512)
    - "Change at Silverwood"
      - Draft, play, unidentified part, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2513)
      - Draft, play, "Scene I," typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2514)
      - Draft, play, typescript carbon, undated (Box 74, Folder 2515)
    - "Charms"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, 1912 August 4 (Box 74, Folder 2516)
    - The Chimaera
      - Publicity, typescript mimeograph (5 copies), undated (Box 74, Folder 2517)
    - "Close Harmony: A Comedy"
      - Draft, play, typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 2518)
    - "Collected Verse"
      - Draft, typescript, typescript carbon, and printed versions, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 2519-2521)
    - "The Colonel: A Study of the Arsenal"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 74, Folder 2522)
    - Columbia Poetry
      - Draft, introduction, typescript, 1936 September (Box 75, Folder 2523)
    - "The Conjuror"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, signed, undated (Box 75, Folder 2524)
    - "Constitution of the Poets"
      - Draft, memorandum, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2525)
    - "Content"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2526)
    - "The Contradictory Byron"
      - Printed version, essay, corrected, with proofreaders' marks, undated (Box 75, Folder 2527)
    - "Cooper Lake"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 75, Folder 2528)
    - "The Cranny in the Sky: The Little Girl's Deposition"
      - Draft, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2529)
    - "Creature of Time"
      - Copy, poem, typescript, annotated in unidentified hand, undated (Box 75, Folder 2530)
    - "Crossing Madison Square"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, corrected, inscribed, and signed, undated (Box 75, Folder 2531)
    - "David's Flight"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 75, Folder 2532)
    - Day of Deliverance: A Book of Poems in Wartime
      - Setting copy, corrected, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations, circa 1944 (Box 75, Folder 2533)
      - Galley proof, corrected and initialed, 1944 (Box 123 (Oversize), Folder 3420)
      - Galley proof sheets (incomplete), corrected, undated (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3340a)
      - Page proof, corrected and initialed, 1944 March (Box 124 (Oversize), Folder 3421)
      - Copy, radio script adaptation, typescript mimeograph (2 copies), undated (Box 75, Folder 2534)
    - "Day of Liberty"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, corrected and signed, undated (Box 75, Folder 2535)
    - "Day's End: Fantasia in One Act"
      - Draft, play, typescript corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2536)
      - Draft, play, annotated in an unidentified hand, possibly by "Charles", undated (Box 75, Folder 2537)
      - Draft, play, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2538)
      - Draft, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 75, Folder 2539)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2540)
      - Draft from The Best One-Act Plays of 1939, typescript and typescript carbon (2 copies), circa 1939 (Box 75, Folder 2541)
    - "Demon Bird"
      - Draft, story, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2542)
    - "Dinner in a [Quels?] Lunch Room"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 2543)
    - "Dorothy Parker's World"
      - Draft, story, typescript, initialed, undated (Box 75, Folder 2544)
    - "Drunken Dirk"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, signed, undated (Box 75, Folder 2545)
    - "Dumb for Happiness"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2546)
    - The Dust Which Is God
      - Draft, interview, typescript, corrected, 1941 (Box 75, Folder 2547)
      - Draft, introduction to extracts, typescript, 1942 July 31 (Box 75, Folder 2548)
      - Draft, [preface?], typescript carbon, undated (Box 75, Folder 2549)
    - "Eden Ever"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, inscribed and signed, 1912 December (Box 75, Folder 2550)
    - "Elinor Wylie"
      - Draft, essay, autograph manuscript, corrected, circa 1927 (Box 75, Folder 2551)
    - "Elinor's World"
      - Draft, prose, typescript, corrected and initaled, undated (Box 75, Folder 2552)
    - "The Evil Sisters: Ezekiel, 23"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2553)
    - "The Fawn in the Snow"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2554)
    - Fifty Poets: An American Auto-Anthology
      - Production file, 1933 (Box 75, Folder 2555)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2556)
    - "The Fire in the Crystal"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3341)
    - "Fire in the Valley: A Play in Three Acts"
      - Draft, play, typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2557)
    - "The First Hole"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 75, Folder 2558)
    - "The Fliers"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, signed, undated (Box 75, Folder 2559)
    - "A Footnote"
      - Draft for First Editions of Modern Authors, typescript, 1946 October 1 (Box 75, Folder 2560)
    - "Forebears"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2561)
      - Draft, poem, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2562)
      - Draft, poem, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2563)
      - Third draft, poem, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 75, Folder 2564)
    - "George Washington"
      - Draft, school essay, autograph manuscript, corrected by teacher, undated (Box 75, Folder 2565)
    - "Ghost Hotel, or, Mrs. Leary's Legacy: Fantasia in One Act"
      - First draft, play, typescript, corrected, 1949 (Box 75, Folder 2566)
    - "The Gilded Man"
      - Research material and notes, 1938, undated (Box 76, Folder 2567-2570)
      - Research material and notes, 1938, undated (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3342)
      - Research material and drafts, 1946, undated (Box 76, Folder 2571-2572)
      - Research material and drafts, 1946, undated (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3343)
    - "Going Abroad Are You?"
      - Draft, [essay?], typescript, corrected, and clippings, undated (Box 77, Folder 2573)
    - "Going Crazy"
      - Collection, typescript, typescript carbon, and clippings, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2574)
    - "Gordon Bottomley's Art"
      - Printed version, review of King Lear's Wife and Other Plays, corrected, with editor's annotations, circa 1922 (Box 77, Folder 2575)
    - "Gothic Poetry"
      - Printed version (incomplete), essay, corrected and annotated, undated (Box 77, Folder 2576)
    - Gruach and Britain's Daughter: Two Plays
      - Printed version, review, corrected, circa 1921 (Box 77, Folder 2577)
    - "Hatshepsu's Search"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2578)
    - "Heine"
      - Draft, essay, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2579)
    - "Henry Canby and William Rose Benét in the Office of the Literary Review"
      - Draft, sketch, typescript, undated (Box 77, Folder 2580)
    - "Henry Martyn Hoyt"
      - Drafts, biographical sketch, autograph manuscript, corrected, and typescript carbon, 1920–1921 (Box 77, Folder 2581)
    - "Holly"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, signed, undated (Box 77, Folder 2582)
    - "Idiosycracy in Eng[lish] Verse"
      - Draft, [lecture?], autograph manuscript, with clippings, undated (Box 77, Folder 2583)
    - "Illusion"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, signed, and typescript, 1921 February 11 (Box 77, Folder 2584)
    - "The Illusion"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, signed, undated (Box 77, Folder 2585)
    - "Impasse"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 77, Folder 2586)
    - "In the Smoking Car"
      - [Galley proof?], poem, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2587)
    - "Introduction"
      - Draft, introduction to Love Poems of Six Centuries, typescript carbon, circa 1950 (Box 77, Folder 2588)
    - [Introduction]
      - Draft, introduction to Second April and The Buck in the Snow by Edna St. Vincent Millay, typescript carbon, circa 1950 (Box 77, Folder 2589)
    - "Island Visit"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 77, Folder 2590)
    - "J. C. Squire, the Poet"
      - Printed version, review of Poems: Second Series, corrected, with editor's annotations, circa 1921 (Box 77, Folder 2591)
    - " Jennifer Lorn by Elinor Wylie"
      - Draft, review, typescript carbon, corrected and signed, circa 1924 (Box 77, Folder 2592)
    - "Jesse James: American Myth"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, inscribed and signed, undated (Box 77, Folder 2593)
    - "Jockeys of Beauty"
      - Printed version, review of The Fleece of Gold by Théophile Gautier, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2594)
    - "Joyance of Jenifer"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 77, Folder 2595)
    - "Keats, After a Century"
      - Printed version, essay, corrected, with editor's annotations, undated (Box 77, Folder 2596)
    - "The Latter Symons"
      - Printed version, review, corrected, with editor's annotations, undated (Box 77, Folder 2597)
    - "Laura Benét and Her Poetry"
      - Draft, essay, typescript, corrected, circa 1950 (Box 77, Folder 2598)
      - Draft, essay, typescript carbon (2 copies), corrected, circa 1950 (Box 77, Folder 2599)
    - "The Laurel Bough: A Comedy of Careers"
      - Notes and drawing, autograph manuscript corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2600)
      - Draft, scenario, typescript carbon, undated (Box 77, Folder 2601)
      - Draft, "Act One," typescript carbon, undated (Box 77, Folder 2602)
    - "Lectures"
      - Draft fragments, autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2603-2604)
    - Lesbia and Other Poems by Arthur Symons
      - Draft, review, typescript, corrected, circa 1920 (Box 77, Folder 2605)
    - "Lights Through the Mist"
      - Printed version, poem, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2606)
    - "Lines To a British Playwright"
      - [Copy?], poem, typescript mimeograph, [?] October 11 (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3344)
    - "The Little Green Man"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, undated (Box 77, Folder 2607)
    - "The Living Miranda"
      - "First" drafts, novel, typescript and autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 77, Folder 2608)
      - Draft, novel, typescript, undated (Box 77, Folder 2609)
    - "Lola Ridge, Impressionist"
      - Printed version, review of Sun-up and Other Poems, corrected, with editor's annotations, circa 1920 (Box 78, Folder 2610)
    - "The Lost Heir of Fantasia"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2611)
    - "The Mad Father's Memory Book, or, a Parent's Strange Meetings"
      - Draft, children's book, autograph manuscript, signed, undated (Box 78, Folder 2612)
    - "Madman's Perspective"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2613)
    - "The Man"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, inscribed and signed, 1914 April (Box 78, Folder 2614)
    - "The Man of Blood"
      - Notes and draft fragments, play, autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2615)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2616)
    - "Mary Shelley's Nightmare"
      - Printed version, review, corrected, with proofreaders' marks, undated (Box 78, Folder 2617)
    - "The Mediaeval Spirit"
      - Printed version, review of The Gothic Rose and Other Poems by Wilfred Rowland Childe, corrected, with proofreaders' marks, circa 1923 (Box 78, Folder 2618)
    - "The Middle Watch: A Poem for Radio"
      - Draft, radio play, typescript, corrected, inscribed and initialed, undated (Box 78, Folder 2619)
    - "Mid-Ocean"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2620)
    - ["Miranda"?]
      - Draft of page 34, novel, typescript, corrected, circa 1941 (Box 78, Folder 2621)
    - "A Mirror of England"
      - Printed version, review of Collected Poems by Edward Thomas, corrected, with editor's annotations, circa 1921 (Box 78, Folder 2622)
    - "The Mixer"
      - Draft, story, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2623)
    - "My Brother Steve"
      - Draft, essay, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2624)
      - Draft, essay, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2625)
      - Draft, essay, "condensed" version, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2626)
      - Draft, essay, "condensed" version, typescript (incomplete), corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2627)
    - ["My first selection is from…"]
      - Draft, address, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2628)
    - "Narrative Verse"
      - Draft, [lecture notes?], typescript, undated (Box 78, Folder 2629)
    - "Note"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected and annotated, undated (Box 78, Folder 2630)
    - "Of Suffering"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2631)
    - "On Beauty"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2632)
    - "On Private View"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 2633)
    - "On the Decay of the Toy Theatre"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, signed, undated (Box 78, Folder 2634)
    - "The One"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, initialed, 1914 February 16 (Box 78, Folder 2635)
    - "Orford Otranto"
      - Printed version, review of The Castle of Otranto by Horace Walpole, with editor's annotations, undated (Box 78, Folder 2636)
    - "Outcast Words"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2637)
    - "Owed to the Dial"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 78, Folder 2638)
    - "The Palace of Bric-a-brac"
      - Draft, poem, typescript, annotated, undated (Box 78, Folder 2639)
    - "The Paper Prince"
      - Draft, motion picture scenario, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2640)
    - "Partial Scenario for a Novel"
      - Draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2641)
    - "Paul [?]"
      - Draft, poem, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 78, Folder 2642)
    - Perpetual Light: A Memorial
      - Setting copy, corrected and annotated, with printer's annotations, 1919 (Box 78, Folder 2643)
    - "Perverse"
      - Draft, poem, typescript carbon, undated (Box 78, Folder 2644)
    - The Phoenix Nest
      - Proof, essay, with proofreaders marks, [?] April 11 (Box 115 (Oversize), Folder 3345)
    - [Poems]
      - Drafts and printed versions, corrected, 1921-1944, undated (Box 78, Folder 2645-2646)
      - Drafts and printed versions, corrected, 1921-1944, undated (Box 79, Folder 2647-2651)
    - "Poems for Marjorie"
      - Drafts, poems, autograph manuscript, typescript, and typescript carbon, signed, 1943, undated (Box 79, Folder 2652)
    - The Poetry of Freedom
      - Drafts, poems, typescript, with printer's annotations, circa 1948 (Box 79, Folder 2653)
    - "Postamble to C.M.'s Explanation"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 79, Folder 2654)
    - "Prayer for England"
      - Draft, musical score with lyrics, autograph manuscript (copy), circa 1940-1941 (Box 79, Folder 2655)
      - Draft, musical score with lyrics, autograph manuscript (copy), undated (Box 79, Folder 2656)
    - "Preamble Under Sirius"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1935 June 17 (Box 79, Folder 2657)